Guide to the Naomi Shihab Nye Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Writings on Nye, 1970-2017, undated
  Writings on Shihab Nye contain clippings and articles newspapers and magazines. Materials are organized into Interviews, Catalogs, Promotion, Events, Reviews, Clippings, and Magazine Articles. The bulk of the materials are from the San Antonio Express-News and the Dallas Morning-News. Of note are articles documenting Nye's early career as traveling poet for schools in Texas, profiles from the towns where she led workshops and conferences, and local coverage from a 1984 trip to South America. Also included are unpublished papers and articles.
  - Interviews, 1980, 1994-2015, undated (Box 43, Folder 1-3)
  - Catalogs, 1978-2014, undated (Box 43, Folder 4-6)
  - Promotion, 1999-2007, undated (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Events, 1980-2016 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Reviews, 1980-2017, undated
    - 1980-2017, undated (Box 44, Folder 1-4)
    - Oversized, 1982-2006 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1970-2017, undated
    The bulk of the articles are from the San Antonio Express-News and the Dallas Morning-News. Also included are articles tracing Nye's early career as traveling poet for schools in Texas, local coverage from a 1984 trip to South America, and profiles from the towns where she led workshops and conferences. Some articles are annotated by Nye and her father, Aziz Shihab.
    - 1970-2017, undated (Box 44, Folder 5-10)
    - Oversized, 1972-2015, undated (Box 53, Folder 2-8)
    - Oversized, 1979-2017 (Box 54, Folder 8-11)
  - Magazine Articles, 1982-2007 (Box 45, Folder 1-5)
- Works by Others, 1920, 1965-2015, undated
  Works by Others include musical and theatrical adaptations of Nye's works, Artist Files compiled by Shihab Nye, and Collected and Received materials. Artist Files include clippings on Ashley Bryan, who illustrated Salting the Ocean: 100 Poems by Young Poets. Artist Files also include drafts, clippings, publications, correspondence, and other materials by Texas writers Roberto Bonazzi, Sandra Cisneros, Albert Huffstickler, Jack Myers, John Phillip Santos, and San Antonio politician Maury Maverick, Jr. Also included are Michael Nye draft and article and considerable writings and correspondence by Nye's father Aziz Shihab. Note that these files organized by Nye are separate from letters found in Series III: Correspondence. Collected and received materials include chapbooks, exhibition catalogs, broadsides, publications, poems, prose, art, and various collected clippings and newspapers.
  - Adaptations, 1997-2015
    - Music, 1997-2015
      - "Jerusalem: Everything Comes Next: a setting of four poems by Naomi Shihab Nye", January 21, 1997 (Box 52, Folder 6)
        Joseph Landers
      - "Poems by Naomi Shihab Nye, music by Laszlo Slomovits", 2010 (Box 45, Folder 6)
        2 audio CDs and correspondence from Slomovits
      - Sheet music, 2004-2015 (Box 45, Folder 7)
        Includes "Dog," "One Boy Told Me," "Mad," "She Tore a Map," and "Kindness."
      - Choral Reading and Program, 2002-2015 (Box 45, Folder 8)
        "My Grandmother's Hands" and "The Art of Disappearing."
    - Theater, 1997-2004
      - "Benito's Dream Bottle", 1997, 2004 (Box 46, Folder 1)
        Program and DVD
      - "Habibi", 2002 (Box 46, Folder 2)
        Screenplay draft with annotations by Nye. Program and promotion.
  - Artist Files, 1985-2011, undated
    - Roberto Bonazzi (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Ashley Bryan (Box 52, Folder 7)
      Oversized clippings
    - Sandra Cisneros (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Mahmoud Darwish (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Albert Huffstickler (Box 46, Folder 6)
      Poems and chapbooks inscribed to Nye
    - Maury Maverick, 1990-1995 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Judith McPheron (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - W. S. Merwin (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Michael Nye, 1985-2005 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Peace Pilgrim (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Alastair Reid (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - John Phillip Santos, circa 1994-1998 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      Drafts, published writings, interview, DVD.
    - Aziz Shihab, 1993-2011, undated
      - A Taste of Palestine, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Does the Land Remember Me?, 1998-2011 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Articles and translations, 1980, 1998, 2003-2005, undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Memorials, 2007 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Oversized clippings (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Rudolph Staffel (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - William Stafford (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Memorials (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Collected and Received Materials, 1981-2014, undated
    - Chapbooks (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Broadsides (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Oversized Broadside (Box 52, Folder 9)
      "I Believe," Gerald Stern
    - Writings on or for Nye (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Poetry (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Prose (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Audio - Visual (Box 48, Folder 6)
      Optical disk and cassette tape
    - Art (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Art, Oversized (Box 52, Folder 10)
      "Naomi Nye," Malon Flato
    - Art, Oversized, 1982, 1987, undated (Map-case Dr. 9)
      "Casa de Laurie," drawing in marker, 9/27/1987; pencil drawing, Marc Chates, Chartres, undated; print, Mona Saudi, "Woman-Bird," 21/50, 1982
    - Publications (Box 48, Folder 8-9)
    - Clippings (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Clippings, Oversized, 1982-2014 (Box 52, Folder 11-12)
    - Printed materials, Oversized (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Arts Magazines, Oversized, 1981-1988, 2001-2002 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Clippings, Oversized, 1989-2014 (Box 55, Folder 1-7)